WILLIAM OPIO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Mobile: +256705165815

E-Mail: johnwilliams1756@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/william-opio/

GitHub: https://github.com/Wil1756

CAREER SUMMARY

Creative software developer specialized in front-end development with a strong emphasis on React, React Native, and JavaScript/TypeScript. Experienced in designing and developing web and mobile applications. Quick learner, team-oriented, and highly motivated with a background in Civil Engineering.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CODE PLAY - UGANDA

Full Stack JavaScript Developer (March 2022 – Present)

- Develope the CodePlay Learning Management System application for university students and researchers.
- Participate in Agile development processes, including daily stand-ups, refinements, and feature planning.
- Use Git and GitHub for version control and collaboration with cross-functional teams.
- Create endpoints using Node.js and ExpressJS, documented with Swagger.
- Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, React Native, Expo,Redux, Hooks, JSX, HTML, and CSS.

CODE PLAY – UGANDA

Software Developer (April 2021 – March 2022)

- Developed a web application for monitoring investment plans using React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and JSX.
- Implemented Redux and Hooks for state management and developed reusable components.
- Consumed REST API data and applied methods to update React component states.
- Collaborated in an Agile environment, participating in code reviews and sprint ceremonies.

FREELANCER

React JS Software Developer (November 2020 – April 2021)

- Developed a client's web content monitoring full-stack application using React, JavaScript, and TypeScript.
- Created reusable React components and implemented user authentication using REST API.
- Collaborated using Git and worked in an Agile/Scrum environment with Jira.

GUANGDONG CONSTRUCTION CO -- KAMPALA

<u>Civil Engineer / Manager (August 2014 – June 2020)</u>

- Oversaw construction projects, ensuring structural integrity and safety compliance.
- Collaborated with various stakeholders and conducted site inspections.
- Managed resources and teams while adhering to project timelines and budgets.

EDUCATION

KYAMBOGO UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Engineering: Civil Engineering

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, TypeScript, JSX
- Frameworks & Libraries: React, React Native, Redux, Hooks
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Express.js, Node.js
- Cloud Technologies: Firebase, AWS (Amplify)
- Creativity and Innovation
- Excellent Communication
- Great Adaptability

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Luganda